<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 14:55:52 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup CI-CD For Hugo Website Using Github Actions</title><link>/post/hugo-ci-cd-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 14:55:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/hugo-ci-cd-using-github-actions/</guid><description>Setup CI/CD For Hugo Website Using Github Actions What is CI/CD? Continuous integration (CI) and continuous delivery (CD) embody a culture, set of operating principles, and collection of practices that enable application development teams to deliver code changes more frequently and reliably.
In short, CI/CD is a way to automate the process of building, testing and deploying code. The cycle of building till deploying is also referred to as pipelining.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes: Core Concepts Primer - Part 1</title><link>/post/k8s-primer-p1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:16:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/k8s-primer-p1/</guid><description>Kubernetes: Core Concepts Primer - Part 1 What is Kubernetes? Kubernetes, also known as K8s, is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
Components of Kubernetes:
API Server: Acts as a interface for users, cli, and other services to interact with the k8s system ETCD: Key-Value store that stores the state, metadata etc. Scheduler: A component that distributes work to nodes in the cluster.</description></item><item><title>Get Started With Minikube on MacOS</title><link>/post/minikube-on-macos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 18:05:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/minikube-on-macos/</guid><description>Get Started With Minikube on MacOS What is Minikube? Minikube is a tool that makes it easy to run Kubernetes locally. It is a one node cluster, where the master and worker processes are on the same machine.
Setup Minikube On MacOS To get started wiht minikube on macOS, we need to install binary for minikube which can be downloaded using the following command:
&amp;lt;!-- For x64-86 --&amp;gt; curl -LO https://storage.</description></item><item><title>Deploy hugo blog on github pages</title><link>/post/hugo-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/hugo-github-pages/</guid><description>Deploy hugo blog on github pages What is Hugo? Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again.
In short, Hugo is a static website generation tool which transforms markdown into beautiful web pages. One can get started with hundreds of available themes or even create a new one.
Let&amp;rsquo;s jump right in.
First of all, we would need to install Hugo.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to my blog</title><link>/post/welcome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/welcome/</guid><description>Diving into blogging. Whatever exciting I come across, I will try to put it down here. Hopefully everyone will enjoy it.</description></item></channel></rss>